musicroom.com 2018-08-16

# Privacy Policy | musicroom.com

**Musicroom** is owned by **Music in Print Ltd.**

Your privacy is of great importance to Musicroom and we strictly abide by privacy laws and regulations. This means that your personal data is safe in our hands and is always used in a proper manner. In this privacy policy, we will explain everything that we at the Musicroom website do with information we acquire about you.

Musicroom.com is committed to keeping the personal details of its visitors and customers private and secure (information is collected and stored in accordance with the new GDPR legislation).

If you have any questions, or would like to know exactly which of your data is stored by us, please contact [help@musicroom.com](mailto:help@musicroom.com).

**Dealing with orders**

If you place an order with us, we will use your personal data to deal with it in a proper manner. We are allowed to pass on your personal data to our delivery service to have your order delivered to you. We will also receive information about your payment from your bank or credit card company.

We use your payment details, name and address details, email address, telephone number and invoice address for this purpose. We need this information for the contract we have concluded with you. We will store this information until your order has been completed and for six years thereafter (pursuant to the statutory retention obligation).

_Provision of data to third parties_

We cooperate with certain companies that may receive your abovementioned personal data from us.

To deal with orders, we work in partnership with:

  * our payment providers – Worldpay & Paypal;
  * our postal operators - Royal Mail & UK Mail.

**‘Contact Us’ form**

You can use the ‘contact us’ form to ask us questions or to make requests.

We use your email address, IP address, telephone number and name and address details for this purpose. We need this information for the contract we have concluded with you. We will store this information until we are certain that you are satisfied with our response and for six months thereafter. This way, we can readily access the information should you have any follow-up questions and train our customer service staff so that the service they provide is better still.

**Email Newsletter**

You may subscribe to our newsletter, in which you will find news, promotions and information about our products and services. You may cancel the subscription at any time. Every email contains a link at the bottom with which you can unsubscribe. Your email address will only be added to the list of subscribers with your consent. These data will be stored until you cancel your subscription. If you would prefer not to receive these mailings, you can update your preferences from Your Account.

Please note that we only send emails to people who have opted in to receive them and where we are replying to an email query. We only store your email address in our mailing list and email you for a  maximum of two years from your last purchase or click on our email, after which you will be automatically unsubscribed.

**Your account**

You will have to register first before you can use certain sections of our website. At this point, you will be required to provide information about yourself and select a user name. We use this to create an account that you can log into with your user name and a password of your choice.

We use your name and address details, telephone number, email address, IP address, musical instrument, invoice address and payment details for purpose. We have a legitimate interest in doing this. We store this information until you cancel the account.

We store this information to prevent you from having to enter it repeatedly and to make it easier for us to contact you should that prove necessary after you have used the website. You can amend information whenever you wish through your account.

We ask for your date of birth to send Happy Birthday emails to you.

We ask for Instrument preferences – you can specify your favourite instrument or genre and opt in so you can  receive tailored and relevant products, offers and content.

We use the personal information you give us for the following purposes.

  * to contact you about the status of your order.
  * to efficiently process and dispatch your order to your delivery address.
  * to change and enhance the web site.
  * to occasionally email you with details of our products, special promotions, recommendations and enhancements – not only on your birthday!
  * to email you for feedback on products purchased and your experience with us via our 3rd party provider – Reevoo.
  * to give you a more personalised browsing and shopping experience.

**  
Advertising**

We would like to send you information advertising offers and new products or services. We do this:

  * by email;
  * via social media.

You may object to receiving such advertising at any time. Every email contains a link with which you can unsubscribe. You may block us or use the unsubscribe option. You can also use your account to indicate that you no longer wish to receive these emails.

**  
Provision of data to other companies or institutions**

With the exception of the abovementioned partners, we will not pass on your personal data to other companies or institutions under any circumstances, unless we are required by law to do so (e.g. if the police demand it in relation to suspicion of an offence having been committed).

Our website includes social media buttons. The administrators of these services use them to collect your personal data.

**  
Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics to keep records of how users use our website. We have concluded a Data Processing Agreement with Google. It contains strict agreements on the data about which they may keep records. We have not given Google consent to use the information obtained from Analytics for other Google services. We arrange for Google to anonymise the IP addresses.

**  
Security**

Protection of personal data is very important to us. We take the following measures to protect your privacy:

  * Access to personal data is protected with a user name and password. We use secure connections (Secure Sockets Layer, or SSL), which ensure that all information transmitted between you and our website is protected when you enter your personal data

**  
Cookie Policy**

We may use technology to track the patterns of behaviour of visitors to our site. This can include using a "cookie" which would be stored on your browser. You can usually modify your browser to prevent this happening. The information collected in this way can be used to identify you unless you modify your browser settings.

We use this information to give you a more tailored and relevant experience when shopping with us and we use this data to improve website functionality and usability.

Note that if you modify your browser to refuse cookies from Musicroom.com, parts of the website may not function as expected.

For a specific list of cookies used on the Musicroom website and an explanation of what they do or to change your cookie preferences, please click here for more information – Cookie Policy information.

**PayPal Transactions**

In addition to the Privacy Policy outlined above, all PayPal transactions placed on the Musicroom website are also subject to the PayPal Privacy Policy. Click here to link to the policy – [Paypal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

**  
LINKS**

The website may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage users to be aware when they leave the website to read the privacy statements of other websites that collect personally identifiable information.

The personal information which we hold will be held securely in accordance with our Security Policy and the law.

**  
Amendments to this privacy statement**

Needless to say, we amend our privacy policy whenever there are any changes to our website. We recommend that you always note the date at the top and check regularly to see if there are any new versions. We will do our best to announce changes separately as well.

**  
Inspecting, amending and removing your data**   
You may contact us at any time if you have any questions or wish to know which of your personal data we hold by emailing [help@musicroom.com](mailto:help@musicroom.com).

You have the following rights:

  * to receive an explanation of what personal data we have collected about you and how we use that data;
  * to inspect the specific personal data that we have collected;
  * to have any errors rectified;
  * to have outdated personal data erased;
  * to withdraw your consent;
  * to object to a specific type of use of the data.

Please always ensure that you make your identity clearly known, so we, in turn, can ensure that we do not modify or delete the data of the wrong person.

We store personal data for 6 years however, in line with new legislation, if you would like us to delete your data completely then click the Delete Account button in the Your Account page.

You can open a new account at any time.

If you have any questions about Musicroom.com's Privacy Policy please email them to [help@musicroom.com](mailto:help@musicroom.com).
